# **Reilly Forshaw**

# Senior Software Engineer

## **Summary**

I am an experienced Software Engineer and full stack thinker. I love API development and think deeply about the process of constructing reliable, performant, maintainable software. I am a beginner hockey player, triathlon finisher, hole-in-one achiever, mountain biker, skier, and Vancouver Canucks fan.

## **Work History**

## **Senior Software Engineer**

Apple - www.apple.com

July 2018 - Present

iOS, macOS, Objective-C, Swift, XCTest, Git, GitHub

Productivity and Creative Apps.

- Design and implement features, often as the directly responsible individual (DRI).
- Fix bugs.

#### Software Engineer, iOS

Facebook - www.facebook.com

October 2016 - July 2018

iOS, Objective-C, C++, WebRTC, XCTest, Google Test, Buck, Mercurial, Phabricator

I worked on the Realtime Platform team at Facebook, supporting apps that provide realtime communication experiences to Facebook users. I worked on both cross-platform C++ and Objective-C libraries. I was the team's iOS expert and drove several projects to improve the platform and helped mentor other engineers.

- Point-of-contact for iOS partner teams (Messenger, Live).
- Led an effort to dramatically reduce (~66%) the binary size impact of our main library by analyzing dependencies and factoring out some code into smaller libraries.
- · Identified and executed on opportunities to improve reliability, code quality, and test coverage of the platform.
- Advocated for iOS/Objective-C best practices to provide an API consistent with iOS engineers' expectations.

### iOS Software Developer, Team Lead

Clio - www.clio.com

June 2013 - September 2016

iOS, Swift, Objective-C, Foundation, UIKit, Core Data, Ruby on Rails, MySQL, REST, Git, GitHub, Jira

I spent most of my time at Clio on the iOS team, and served as team lead during my last year. Before that, I worked on various parts of the Ruby on Rails app, including the public REST API, feature work, and MySQL query performance.

- Responsible for consistent output of the iOS team biweekly App Store releases, major releases for trade shows.
- Refactored search feature as a pilot project for the team to evaluate Functional Reactive Programming and Model-View-View Model (MVVM) architecture.
- Made extensive improvements to the calendar feature, improving accuracy while dramatically improving
  performance. I don't have performance numbers here but, qualitatively, it went from being barely usable to
  running smoothly for Clio's biggest accounts.
- Was a key contributor to the iOS code base in all areas, including networking, persistence, UI, testing, and CI maintenance.
- Provided technical mentorship to other developers via 1-on-1's, code review, lunch & learns, and facilitating group learning opportunities.
- Maintained public REST API and provided support to external developers.

## **Software Engineer**

Clinicbook (Acquired by CareCru) - www.clinicbook.com

October 2010 - June 2013

Java, Ruby on Rails

I joined Clinicbook as the first full-time employee. We built an online booking and appointment reminder system for healthcare appointments.

- Built application for syncing schedules and receiving notifications about scheduled and confirmed appointments.
- Participated in technical due diligence discussions during fundraising.

## **Education**

*The University of British Columbia*, 2010 Bachelor of Applied Science in Electrical Engineering

## References

Available upon request